Benson Kimtai Ndiwa

Nairobi, Kenya +254707357072 bnkimtai@gmail.com

A solution-driven web developer adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment and finding solutions. I have proven experience developing consumer-focused web applications. I possess good knowledge of the best practices for web design, user experience, security and speed.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance - Software Developer

Jun. 2022 - Present

- Completed multiple projects for clients on time and within budget, leading to increased repeat business and positive references.
- ➤ Worked with clients to understand their specific needs and develop custom software solutions tailored to their requirements

Darna Limited, Nairobi - Software Developer

Jun. 2021 - May. 2022

- Delivered a software project ahead of schedule and under budget, resulting in increased client satisfaction and repeat business.
- ➤ Developed and implemented a new feature that improved performance by 30%, reducing processing time and increasing efficiency.
- ➤ Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify and solve complex technical problems, resulting in improved product stability and customer satisfaction.

The National Treasury, Nairobi - Industrial Attache

Apr. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- ➤ Implemented a new network infrastructure, improving reliability and increasing connectivity for the organization and its partners.
- ➤ Resolved complex technical issues and provided expert support, reducing downtime and increasing productivity for employees and partners.

EDUCATION

Multimedia University of Kenya

Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2022

Bsc. Information technology

SKILLS

Full Stack Web Development

Desktop Applications

Bash Scripting

Docker

AWS Cloud Computing

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Javascript

ReactJs

NodeJS

Python

C#

MongoDB

SQL

PHP

LANGUAGES

English

Kiswahili

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/benson-kimtai-ndiwa

Portfolio

https://benndiwa.netlify.com

Github

https://github.com/Benson306

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner

AWS Re/start program May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

PROJECTS

Ecommerce Web Application

An ecommerce web application with Cart, User dashboard and working payment options available. It also has an admin panel for management of orders, deliveries, products and delivery locations. Developed with React, Node.js, Express, MongoDb and Tailwind CSS

Real Estate Management System

A web application that enables real estate professionals to track residents, leases, maintenance tasks, collect rent, and handle finances to update operations and reduce costs. Developed with PHP, MySQL, CSS and uses the Safaricom Daraja API for mobile payment.

Utulivu Shopping Cart

A web application that allows a customer to browse, grab a product off the shelf, and head to the checkout counter to make a purchase. It has capability for enabling instant mobile payment. Developed with React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDb and Tailwind CSS.

Hospital ERP

A web application that aims at bringing quality in patient care & management with various important utilities like easy & quick patient registration, instant access to patient's complete health history, integrated patient module with various other related departments and many more. Developed with PHP, Javascript, MySQL and uses Mpdf to generate pdf receipts and records.

Brindex Course Search

A course finder application to compare diploma, undergraduate and postgraduate courses from colleges, top universities and higher education institutions across Kenya, including entry requirements. Developed with PHP, Javascript and MySQL

REFEREES

Nathan Rugut - Managing
Director Darna Limited
darnaworksltd@gmail.com

Dr. Bosco Okumu - Deputy Chief Economist, The National Treasury. kodhis2000@gmail.com